A Guide to the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad ledgers, 1834-1912
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad ledgers, 1834-1912
Library of Virginia
53925
22 volumes.
Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased
Historical Information
The Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad (RF&P) was incorporated by an Act of the General Assembly of Virginia on 25 February 1834. It was at the time the sixth railroad to be chartered in Virginia. The company's purpose was to provide rail service from Richmond to the Potomac River near Washington, D.C. The RF&P ceased to exist in 1991, when it was merged into the CSX Corporation.
Scope and Content
Ledgers, 1834-1912, of the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad (RF&P) consisting of nineteen ledgers, 1834-1905, containing business accounts and expenses for the RF&P; one ledger, 1852-1860, containing accounts and expenses for the Washington and Fredericksburg Steamboat Company (1852-1854) and for the Potomac Steamboat Company (1854-1860); and two volumes for the Washington Southern Railway Company, a journal, 1893-1912, containing accounts, and a volume of annual reports, 1899-1908, to the Interstate Commerce Commission, both for the Washington Southern Railway Company. The steamboat companies and the Washington Southern Railway were subsidiaries of the RF&P.
Related Material
Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad records, 1834-1997 (LVA accession 36460)
Contents List
- RF&P, 1834-1848 (indexed) (Ledger A)
- RF&P, 1834-1836 (Ledger A)
- Washington and Fredericksburg Steamboat Company, Potomac Steamboat Company, 1852-1860 (Ledger A)
- RF&P, 1848-1852 (Ledger B)
- RF&P, 1852-1858 (indexed) (Ledger C)
- RF&P, 1858-1860 (indexed) (Ledger D)
- RF&P, 1860-1865 (indexed) (Ledger E)
- RF&P, 1865-1867 (indexed) (Ledger F)
- RF&P, 1867-1870 (indexed) (Ledger G)
- RF&P, 1870-1874 (indexed) (Ledger H)
- RF&P, 1874-1877 (indexed) (Ledger J)
- RF&P, 1877-1880 (indexed) (Ledger K)
- RF&P, 1880-1883 (indexed) (Ledger L)
- RF&P, 1883-1886 (indexed) (Ledger M)
- RF&P, 1886-1889 (indexed) (Ledger N)
- RF&P, 1889-1892 (indexed) (Ledger O)
- RF&P, 1892-1895 (indexed) (Ledger P)
- RF&P, 1895-1898 (indexed) (Ledger Q)
- RF&P, 1898-1901 (indexed) (Ledger R)
- RF&P, 1901-1905 (indexed) (Ledger S)
- Washington Southern Railway, 1893-1912
- Washington Southern Railway annual reports to the Interstate Commerce Commission, 1899-1908